Hey everyone, and thanks for jumping
back into the cryptoverse.
Today, we're going to talk about Bitcoin
and how a decision will eventually be
forced. If you guys like the content,
make sure you subscribe to the channel,
give the video a thumbs up, and check
out the sale on Into the Cryptoverse
Premium at intothecryptoverse.com. As
always,
uh we got a lot of people signing up for
the conference, so that's great to see.
I'm looking forward to seeing you guys
there. Uh make sure you check it out if
you have not gotten your ticket yet. The
ITC conference, Investing Through the
Cycles, in Miami, November 20th through
the 22nd. Link is in the description
below or the pinned comment. Bitcoin is
currently trading around 63.5.
And as you can see, in about 9 seconds,
we're going to get an update to both the
bear market resistance band and the
200-week moving average. So, let's
awkwardly just wait. 3 2 1 and 0. So,
now we have a new candle. The bear
market resistance band is currently at
around 69k.
The 200-week moving average is around
63.7k.
Now,
I think we technically Do we close above
it last week? So, last week, the
200-week was at 63.5.
So, 63,551,
and Bitcoin closed at 63,500. So,
a little bit below it, but
you know, pretty pretty much near it.
But, the argument of the video is This
is going to be a very short video. Um
you know, we have a newborn in the
house. I'm not sleeping a whole lot
right now. So, we got to make this one
short and sweet.
You got
two things happening, right? You have
the bear market resistance band kind of
coming down. You have the 200-week
moving average coming up.
And
you're going to have a decision, right,
that that is going to have to be made
before the end of the year, in my
opinion, right? And and and probably
within the next couple of months.
Because there's only so much longer that
the bear market resistance band can go
down and the 200-week moving average can
go up before a decision has to be made.
Are we going to break above the bear
market resistance band, or are we going
to break below the 200-week moving
average? Now, in order for a lot of the
on-chain indicators to reset, it would
imply going a little bit lower. Right?
Like if you look at historically, and a
lot of people get upset when I talk
about this stuff, and I can't for the
life of me figure out why. Like I, you
know, these are just on-chain indicators
that everyone can look at. You know,
it's not like you don't have access to
the same
to the same things. I mean, you can look
up what the NVRV Z-score is, and you can
see how it tends to bottom out below
zero, and it's not there yet. It's
pretty close. I'm not suggesting that
you can't DCA Bitcoin. Normally, DCAing
in the second half of mid-term years is
the right long-term strategy.
But, without sort of another
move lower a little bit later in the
year, it would still leave some of the
on-chain indicators not fully reset.
Now, if you look at 2022,
Bitcoin got below the 200-week moving
average, worked its way back up, had a
red week just like we had right there,
and then had a green week, and and that
green week occurred early August, and
then you had a larger drawdown. Now, if
you look at 2018,
the drop occurred basically right when
you got into August. So, I can't begin
to tell you, you know, exactly what week
it's going to occur before Bitcoin
likely heads back down below 60K. Like I
don't know exactly what week it's going
to occur,
but I would also say this, there's no
guarantee that you make it uh back up to
these levels. I know it looks like it's
obvious, and like I would say, all
right, yeah, that would make sense, but
in 2022, we didn't make it to the bear
market resistance band before getting
the August correction. Right? We got
close, but we didn't actually hit the
bear market resistance band again until
October. And by the time we hit it, it
was actually a lot lower than the price
of Bitcoin was trading in August,
because the bear market resistance band
continued to come down. So,
I'm not here to promise you any
short-term price action. Again, as I've
said before, short-term price action is
akin to geometric Brownian motion. It's
a random walk. You cannot hope to
predict it. But, what I am saying is
that these two
levels are going to force Bitcoin to
make a decision, and once the decision
is made, volatility is going to pick up
a lot. The way it historically has
worked is, you know, volatility like
dies off in the summer, and then you get
a drop, and then it kind of resets
everything, and then you go up. You can
see it happen in 2022. It happened in
2018. And and then it happened again in
like, you know, in in 2014. And so, you
could argue that volatility has kind of
died out. And when you look at the
year-to-date ROI of Bitcoin in 2026,
and compare it to the average of prior
midterm years, and overlay one standard
deviation to that average, we're
basically tracking the average, just
slightly elevated. And you can see that
we're kind of starting to enter the
window of weakness. There's still, you
know, maybe like a latent week. There's
still like a potentially a week left
where Bitcoin could show some strength
if it wants to. But, I would say by mid
to late August, you would really start
to expect that window of weakness to
kind of open back up. We've been in a
window of strength for the month of
July, and the reason we said we're going
to likely going to see a month of
a window of strength in July is because
often times July midterm years, look at
July 2022, up 20%. July 2018, up almost
40%. This July, up 7%. A lot of times
July's green for Bitcoin, and this time
proved no different. The problem is
every prior midterm year was red for
August. Negative 15% in 2022, negative
15% in 2018, negative 18% in 2014, even
in 2010, negative 5%. So, you know, if
Bitcoin were to drop, just say 10% or
so, over the course of the month, that
basically puts it at a slightly new low,
you know, and I'm not saying it has to
go that low right now, but and maybe it
goes up first before it comes down, but
the point is is like this is how it's
normally put out and there's a lot of
people as always,
um
I think they meet, you know, probably
twice a week on Twitter.
Uh they have a mental gymnastics class
where they go through how if everyone's
predicting something to happen then it
won't happen, but then all this stuff
just keeps on happening anyways. Like I
can't tell you how many times they've
said this. Like, oh, it won't it won't
find a low in February. Just because it
does that all the time doesn't mean it
will. Or it won't top in Q4 because
everyone's expecting the four-year cycle
to play out, therefore it won't. And
then it did anyways. And then the whole
sell in May and go away, right? Which we
talked about. Normally May is a local
top in midterm years. Sometimes it
occurs a little bit sooner, but often
times May can be a local top, April-May
time frame, and it did it once again.
So,
you can go meet with the mental
gymnastics club,
and maybe they'll be right. Like, I
don't know, but I mean the point is is
this stuff just keeps on playing out the
same way it always plays out. And I got
too many other things going on in my
life to care too much about, you know,
if I'm going to get the right week
exactly.
Um
so, those are my views, right? Those are
my views. We'll see how it plays out. Uh
you guys know my thoughts. If you guys
like the content, make sure you
subscribe, give the video a thumbs up.
And again,
hope to see you at the ITC conference.
We placed it near the end of November.
The reason it's near the end of
November, I was wanting to do it late
enough in the year where either the
market cycle bottom is in or it's really
close to being in. And I think by the
end of November, it's either going to be
in or really, really close to being in.
I'd love to see you guys there. Check it
out. We're even going to have an ITC
party. Um now, that's open uh to the all
the tiers now as as people continue to
to sign up, I you know, we might be
uh limited on room. Um we're not limited
yet on the room. We have a big enough
space to so have people, but as people
continue to sign up, I'm not really sure
uh what that's going to look like, but I
would encourage you guys to go check out
the page, check out the speakers. Thank
you guys for tuning in, subscribe, and
I'll see you next time. Bye.